Ford Focus on algorithm.
For Ferguson, algorithm is a gritty approach for calculating the maximum possible flow in a network
choreograph.
A term flow network is used to describe a network of vertices and edges with a source s and seemed to
each vertex except s and T can receive and send an equal amount of stuff through it, as can only send
and they can only receive stuff.
We can visualize their understanding of the algorithm using a flow of liquid inside the network of pipes
of different capacities.
Each pipe has a certain capacity of liquid.
It can transfer at an instance.
So for this algorithm, we are going to find how much liquid can be flowed from source to the sink at
an instance using the network.
Consider the following exercise.
Says the following exercise that we can understand it, so the Flow Network Graph asks to t.
So the source and death sink.
A, B, C and D.
The flow is a zero.
From B to D is that flow is zero and the total capacity is two.
So here presenting the capacity as to and slash and the flow here is at the zero.
So from B to T till now there is no flow and the total flow capacity from B to T is two and otherwise.
And other other sources like A to B, B to D to be in the same or the same thing that flow and the capacity
flow and the capacity flow and the capacity so.
The algorithm follows.
The initial initialized the flow in all the edges to zero, this is what we have learned in this picture.
We enclose the flow in all edges is zero why there is an augmenting path between the source and the
sink at the path to the flow and update.
That is it.
That is the jewel graph.
We will learn in the following example how to update and how to add the path to the flow.
OK, we can also consider a reverse path if required, because if we want, if we don't consider them,
we may never find a maximum flow.
Note that if the kapatid capacity for any edge is full, then that path cannot be used.
The above concepts can be understood to be there following exercise.
So let's learn about the Ford Focus and algorithm in a good example.
Please write these down.
These examples are very important, and we will try to implement them in C and in Java.
So.
The flow for of all edges is zero at the beginning.
This is the first step initialize them to zero.
We need to go from as to T and to see them in the maximum flow that we can pass from as to.
Select any arbitrary path from S30 in this step, we have selected to pass as a B and C, the minimum
capacity among the three edges is to do so because the minimum, the minimum flow here between eight.
Minimum get eight, nine and two, which is two, so we add, do we update the graph here?
We update the floor with two two overnight and two over.
So.
Two over two.
As for the minimum capacity, among the three edges is to be to T based on this update, the flow capacity
for each breath.
Now select another pass from S to T, so we could pass through as B C D, the minimum capacity among
these edges is three, three, four and five.
So we select three.
We update their capacities of S, the C and the path with three.
So three over three, three over four.
Three over five.
This is full.
And this is full.
Now.
Let's consider the reverse reverse path.
B D.
This is the reverse path we can go reverse selecting the path as a b, the C D, the minimum residual
capacity among them is the C, which is why because three four minus three is one.
So we add one to all of these data.
So three over eight, three over nine, we have one over seven.
This is the dotted line and four over four becomes four.
So this fall?
This is four and this is four.
The capacity, the capacity for forward and reverse passes are considered separately.
So adding all the flows that we have at the first, which is to.
And the second one is three.
And the last one, which is one, it becomes six.
So the maximum possible flow on the flow network is six.
This is Ford Focus, an algorithm that we have created now that we have learned.
Now let's move to Ford Focus on implementation in C compiler and next.